SENIOR UX DESIGNER & STRATEGIST

Anantha Chickanayakanahalli

PROFILE

Versatile product design consultant and researcher with over 9 years of experience in the technology industry. Specializing in B2B/B2C enterprise products and Air Traffic Control HMI, I apply design thinking and human factors to solve complex problems.

I am adept at creating customer-facing mobile-first & responsive web apps with high accessibility standards (AA & AAA), designing for full HD/4K HMI touchscreens and effectively communicating design process/results to various stakeholders. I have worked with clients such as Franklin Templeton, DBS Bank, Changi Airport, Dubai Airport, Incheon Airport, AVIS-Budget Co, Toyota, Unilever, Time Inc., VFS Global.

View my work here - https://bit.ly/ananthaportfolio

SKILLS

- UX (Interaction) Design, User Research, User journey mapping/Persona mapping, Information Architecture, Wire-framing, Rapid Low-fidelity & Hi-fidelity Prototyping, conducting Discovery Workshops/User interviews/Usability Testing (Scripts, Topic Mapping, Contextual Inquiry, Primary & Secondary Research Synthesis/Reporting), Service blueprints, Affinity mapping
- UI (Visual) Design, Storyboarding, Data Visualization, Authoring Style Guides
- Mobile First Design, Responsive Web Design, XR Design/Development

EXPERIENCE

LEAD XR DESIGNER, IRULE KIDS TV - 2023-PRESENT

- Defining technology strategy XR platforms, Unity game engine for multiplayer support, tools, architecture and methodologies.
- Building, mentoring & collaborating with team (designers, artists, and XR/mobile developers), guiding the product lifecycle – creation of user stories, gameplay, reward systems, level designs, while overseeing design and coding standards, project management, budgets & resources.

- Enhancing XR experience (ensuring age-appropriate and engaging user experience) for children by putting them at the centre of the entire product.
- Planning testing for MVP prototypes and forming strategic partnerships with vendors/experts.

UX RESEARCHER, MAGNIFY DIGITAL & OCAD UNIVERSITY – 2022-2023

- User Research and design of the tool used by Film producers for analyzing and measuring the success of a media product, its critical reception, and its impacts on audiences and applying the insights learned into the tool design.
- Helped define the framework and metrics that go into the back of the Qualitative Analysis Toolkit churning out the numbers/ranking.
- Tools used Google Sheets for collecting data, Procreate for information architecture/mapping, Figma for wire-framing and prototyping.

ADVANCED UX DESIGNER, HONEYWELL - 2019-2021

- Lead for various critical B2B touch screen interface projects (UX strategy + artifacts for the development team) for Honeywell Airports Business.
- The product called <u>Honeywell Turnaround Manager</u> (for Apron Controllers to operate gates) got shipped in 2021 Desktop App (used in the ATC Tower) + Manual Control Board Tablet App (used at each gate). It has provided a 30-40% increase in ATC and airfield ground operation activities in each airport. Conducted contextual inquiry and usability testing of prototype, which included creating user interview scripts, testing with gate management personnel and apron controllers, and generating a user research synthesis report. Incorporated feedback into Backlog and subsequent sprints, adhering to Safe Agile process for continuous improvement.
- Worked on updates for Engineering AirField Manager, a tablet interface for Air Field Maintenance engineers to be able to do critical time bound maintenance activities on the airfield. Developed many features for Air Traffic Control Interface, which is a 4K Touchscreen.
 Being a very high impact and mission critical UI, it follows the standards set by International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO).

 Tools used - MS Powerpoint for wire-framing and Adobe Illustrator (Adobe Creative Cloud) for Visual Design, Axure RP for creating Clickable Prototypes

DESIGN CONSULTANT, MINDTREE - 2014-2019

- Created User Experience Design for a diverse array of SaaS B2B and B2C projects for UK/EU/US, UAE & Singapore clients spanning industries such as Media, Hospitality, Tourism, Banking and Finance, Insurance, Consumer Products, and Manufacturing. UX project lead (teams of six each) for two large digital transformation projects (Hospitality domain & BFSI domains) stretching for a year each.
- Led the end-to-end development of a data analytics product for demand planning and assortment supply, supporting pre-sales efforts and successfully delivering projects for multiple clients.
- Fostered collaboration across development, product management, and design teams, employing lean methods and a double diamond design approach. Consistently delivered high-quality design artifacts throughout all project stages, showcasing adaptability to various contexts and requirements.
- Awarded Outstanding Performer for the year 2017. Received commendations from clients as well as from Mindtree organization for my work: Mastermind (expert thinking), A-Team (exemplary team spirit), Hats Off (extraordinary results).
- Tools used Xmind for information architecture. MS Powerpoint, Adobe Fireworks, Adobe XD for wireframing. Figma, Sketch and Adobe Photoshop for Visual Design. Invisionapp and Justinmind for creating Clickable Prototypes & simulating validation, Zeplin for design handoff of design specifications for development.

UX DESIGNER, IDEUS CONCEPTS – 2013-2014

- Working as a designer within a small team (of four) allowed me to develop and excel in creating exceptional product experiences for a range of industries, including Tourism, Travel, Digital Marketing, and Electronic Design Automation, among others.
- This experience fostered a strong foundation in adaptability and versatility while delivering impactful design solutions across various sectors for B2Bs and B2Cs.
- Tools used Sketch for creating wireframes, Xmind for Information Architecture and Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator for Visual Design

UI DESIGNER, SYMANTEC – 2011-2012

- Working as a designer within a small team (of four) allowed me to develop and excel in creating exceptional product experiences for a range of industries, including Tourism, Travel, Digital Marketing, and Electronic Design Automation, among others.
- This experience fostered a strong foundation in adaptability and versatility while delivering impactful design solutions across various sectors for B2Bs and B2Cs.
- Tools used Sketch for creating wireframes, Xmind for Information
 Architecture and Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator for Visual Design

CERTIFICATIONS

- Accessibility for Ontarians with Disabilities Act (OSG, Canada, 2023)
- Technology Reviewer (eCampus Ontario, Canada, 2023)

AWARDS

Outstanding Performer of the Year 2017 (Mindtree), Mastermind Award (Mindtree), Unstoppable Award (Mindtree), A-Team Award (Mindtree)

EDUCATION

OCAD University, Canada – MDes, 2023

 Tools used - Unity, AR Foundation, AR Core, ARKit, Xcode, Android Studio for mixed reality storytelling and deployment of mixed reality storytelling (https://bit.ly/ananthathesis). P5JS, Arduino, Touch Designer - Experiences and Interfaces installations. HTML, CSS, JS, React, NodeJS, Bootstrap (persianmastersvoice.com)

Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, India – MDes, 2011

 Tools used - Xmind for information architecture. MS Powerpoint, Adobe Fireworks for wireframing. Adobe Primiere, Adobe Photoshop & Adobe Flash for Animation/video.

Bangalore University, India – BArch, 2009

• Tools used - Autocad, 3d Studio Max and Sketchup for 3d moddelling & rendering, Adobe Photoshop for rendering.